<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Weekly Typed</title>
 <link href="http://jayraj.net/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://jayraj.net"/>
 <updated>2015-04-15T22:45:45-07:00</updated>
 <id>http://jayraj.net</id>
 <author>
   <name>Jayraj Jog</name>
   <email>jog@jayraj.net</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Goals for 2015</title>
   <link href="http://jayraj.net/Goals-2015"/>
   <updated>2015-01-04T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://jayraj.net/Goals-2015</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the first time ever, I&amp;#39;ve decided to set some goals for the year for myself. Like most people, consciously committing to something is the best way to get it done. Here we go:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Personal&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn to do at least 5 keepie-uppies with both feet and thighs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Squat at least my own bodyweight (ie a bar loaded with as much as I weigh)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go on at least 5 day hikes over 10 miles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go camping at least 5 times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read at &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/reading_list.html&quot;&gt;least 20 books&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get to level 16 in Duolingo French&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Technical&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write a simple HTTP server in any one of: Python, JavaScript, Clojure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Solve at least 75 exercises on HackerRank&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy 2015 to everyone!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Home row arrow keys</title>
   <link href="http://jayraj.net/Home-row-arrow-keys"/>
   <updated>2014-11-09T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://jayraj.net/Home-row-arrow-keys</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.coolaj86.com&quot;&gt;AJ ONeal&lt;/a&gt;, author of &lt;a href=&quot;http://dear.desi&quot;&gt;Desi&lt;/a&gt;, wrote up &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.coolaj86.com/articles/home-row-arrow-keys-on-os-x-with-karabiner.html&quot;&gt;another way to do it&lt;/a&gt;. My own way to do it is based on &lt;a href=&quot;http://msol.io/blog/tech/2014/03/10/work-more-efficiently-on-your-mac-for-developers/&quot;&gt;this blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;..Continued&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;#39;t even know it, but I was tired of taking my hands off home row to use the arrow keys. Inspired by &lt;a href=&quot;http://duartes.org/gustavo/blog/post/home-row-computing/&quot;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt;, I decided to set up my MacBook Pro to use Caps Lock + IJKL instead of arrow keys. Here&amp;#39;s how I did it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download and install &lt;a href=&quot;https://pqrs.org/osx/karabiner/&quot;&gt;Karabiner&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://pqrs.org/osx/karabiner/seil.html.en&quot;&gt;Seil&lt;/a&gt;. Seil helps you remap the Caps Lock key and Karabiner helps you remap everything else. At this point, I&amp;#39;m unclear why you need two separate apps to do this though&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run Seil and remap the Caps Lock key to the Fn key (code 63), as in the screenshot. &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/seil.png&quot; alt=&quot;Remapping Caps Lock Key to Fn Key&quot; title=&quot;Seil Remapping Caps Lock key&quot;&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Run Karabiner and open &lt;code&gt;private.xml&lt;/code&gt; from &amp;quot;Misc &amp;amp; Uninstall&amp;quot;. &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/privatexml.png&quot; alt=&quot;Opening private.xml&quot; title=&quot;Click on Misc &amp;amp; Uninstall and private.xml&quot;&gt; Put your desired mappings in &lt;code&gt;private.xml&lt;/code&gt;. Mine, below, map Fn+IJKL to their respective arrow keys:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;text language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;?xml version=&amp;quot;1.0&amp;quot;?&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;root&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;item&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;name&amp;gt;Bind CapsLock + J to left arrow&amp;lt;/name&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;identifier&amp;gt;private.caps_leftarrow&amp;lt;/identifier&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;autogen&amp;gt;
            __KeyToKey__ 
            KeyCode::J, ModifierFlag::FN,
            KeyCode::CURSOR_LEFT
        &amp;lt;/autogen&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/item&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;item&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;name&amp;gt;Bind CapsLock + K to down arrow&amp;lt;/name&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;identifier&amp;gt;private.caps_downarrow&amp;lt;/identifier&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;autogen&amp;gt;
            __KeyToKey__ 
            KeyCode::K, ModifierFlag::FN,
            KeyCode::CURSOR_DOWN
        &amp;lt;/autogen&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/item&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;item&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;name&amp;gt;Bind CapsLock + L to right arrow&amp;lt;/name&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;identifier&amp;gt;private.caps_rightarrow&amp;lt;/identifier&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;autogen&amp;gt;
            __KeyToKey__ 
            KeyCode::L, ModifierFlag::FN,
            KeyCode::CURSOR_RIGHT
        &amp;lt;/autogen&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/item&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;item&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;name&amp;gt;Bind CapsLock + I to up arrow&amp;lt;/name&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;identifier&amp;gt;private.caps_uparrow&amp;lt;/identifier&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;autogen&amp;gt;
            __KeyToKey__ 
            KeyCode::I, ModifierFlag::FN,
            KeyCode::CURSOR_UP
        &amp;lt;/autogen&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/item&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/root&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Click &amp;quot;Reload XML&amp;quot; in &amp;quot;Change Key&amp;quot;. Your new mappings should show up in the list. Activate them by clicking on the check box next to them. &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/karabinermappings.png&quot; alt=&quot;Activate remappings&quot; title=&quot;Activate remappings by checking checkboxes&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#39;s it. You can now enjoy greater productivity :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Learning to Juggle</title>
   <link href="http://jayraj.net/Learning-to-Juggle"/>
   <updated>2014-05-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://jayraj.net/Learning-to-Juggle</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In January of this year, I started learning how to juggle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I work at &lt;a href=&quot;http://bittorrent.com&quot;&gt;BitTorrent&lt;/a&gt;, where it appears there&amp;#39;s a bit of a juggling culture. Actually, I don&amp;#39;t know if that&amp;#39;s true, but &lt;strong&gt;everyone&lt;/strong&gt; here seems to juggle. I think it starts from the top; I&amp;#39;ve seen Bram Cohen juggle 5 balls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always thought I lacked the co-ordination to learn to juggle, but it turns out I&amp;#39;d been doing it wrong. I checked out &lt;a href=&quot;link&quot;&gt;this Youtube video&lt;/a&gt; where the guy explains that the simplest method to learn is the 3-ball cascade. Most beginners try to do a pattern where they pass the ball underhand. Although this seems like the most obvious way to juggle, it&amp;#39;s actually really hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cascade style is easy to pick up, once you&amp;#39;ve developed the muscle memory. Just do what the guy in the video says and you&amp;#39;ll be juggling within 3 to 4 weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Reading List</title>
   <link href="http://jayraj.net/Reading-List"/>
   <updated>2014-04-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://jayraj.net/Reading-List</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I now have a &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/reading_list.html&quot;&gt;reading list&lt;/a&gt; on my blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, it&amp;#39;s divided into fiction and non-fiction, with non-fiction further divided into technical and non-technical books. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a mental list of books that I want to read, but always draw a blank when I&amp;#39;m actually at the library. This list will help with that. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first book I read on the list was &lt;i&gt;On Writing&lt;/i&gt; by Stephen King. I&amp;#39;ve read plenty of fiction by Stephen King. Some good (&lt;i&gt;Everything&amp;#39;s Eventual&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;The Dead Zone&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;The Running Man&lt;/i&gt;, the sometimes sappy &lt;i&gt;Hearts in Atlantis&lt;/i&gt;), and some very forgettable (&lt;i&gt;The Regulators&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;The Girl Who Loved Tom Gordon&lt;/i&gt;). So I&amp;#39;ve been meaning to hear the great man talk about his craft. He did not disappoint me. But now, in his classification of writers (great, good, competent, bad), I worry that I am one of the bad ones. The ones who he says can never become competent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reading list page also has Amazon.com referral links. I don&amp;#39;t really need the money; it&amp;#39;s just a way of keeping score. I will donate any cash I make from the page to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://eff.com&quot;&gt;EFF&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Fixing my TV</title>
   <link href="http://jayraj.net/Fixing-my-TV"/>
   <updated>2014-03-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://jayraj.net/Fixing-my-TV</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last month, I fixed my 56-inch Samsung digital light projection (DLP) TV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For 3 months, it made a screaming, buzzing noise when I turned it on. I made it stop by thumping it on the back. We had bought it for $100 off Craigslist; it was just sitting in someone&amp;#39;s garage. At the time, we felt great about it for financial and environmental reasons. And now, this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;#39;t bother looking up TV repair services. It would cost more than the TV had cost in the first place. Besides, I would be cheating myself out of a learning opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The actual process turned out to be easy. I found out what the possible problem was by Googling variations of &amp;quot;Samsumg DLP tv noise&amp;quot;. Looked like it might be a bad color wheel. Found out how to tell for sure. Opened up the TV and determined that it was indeed the case. Ordered a new color wheel and followed instructions on Youtube to install it. It took about 2 hours of work spread out over 2 weekends: 1.5 hours to research, open up the TV, find the malfunctioning part and order a replacement, 0.5 to put the part in and sew the patient back up. I learned a lot:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take a lot of pictures as you are doing the disassembling. Put the screws in labeled cups or bowls so you don&amp;#39;t lose them or lose track of which one goes where&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In most cases, watching a video that demos the repair you&amp;#39;re attempting, even if it&amp;#39;s not for the same model, is better than reading instructions for your particular model&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you feel stuck, take a break, then re-watch the part of the instructional video you&amp;#39;re having trouble with (or re-read the instructions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;#39;s always useful to have good tools. I have a Rosewill computer repair toolkit that I bought for $20. It&amp;#39;s been useful on many occasions since&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doing basic repairs like this gives you the confidence to tackle more complicated projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m a big believer in repairing your electronics. People don&amp;#39;t repair their stuff in the Western world. Having someone repair it can cost more than it would to buy it new. It&amp;#39;s a terrible waste and disastrous for the environment. On the other hand, some entrepreneurial person could probably make a decent living by buying (or getting for free) broken stuff, fixing it and selling it on.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Car Dependent vs Car Enhanced</title>
   <link href="http://jayraj.net/Car-Dependent-vs-Car-Enhanced"/>
   <updated>2014-03-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://jayraj.net/Car-Dependent-vs-Car-Enhanced</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Warning: This is a non-technical, lifestyle post&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I consider my life to be &amp;quot;car-enhanced&amp;quot;, not car-dependent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started when I was shopping for new insurance this year. I had to re-familiarize myself with the difference between &amp;quot;Comprehensive Coverage&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Collision Coverage&amp;quot;, and the quote included something called &amp;quot;Rental reimbursement&amp;quot;. Reading details, I realized it covered the cost of a rental car in case my car was in the shop being repaired after an accident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This possibility had never crossed my mind. I always assumed that if my car was in the shop for a few days, I would just be car-less for that duration. Which didn&amp;#39;t sound terrible to me; I just wouldn&amp;#39;t be able to go out of town on a weekend without renting a car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thinking about it further though, if this type of coverage is offered, it means people need it. People prefer to have a rental car and pay money for it while their own car is being worked on. They need it to get to work, pick up kids from school/daycare, buy groceries, whatevs. They are car-dependent; they literally cannot function without an internal combustion engine in their driveway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me and the missus, none of these things apply. I take the train to work, she takes the bus to school. We bike to buy groceries and for most other errands and funtimes within a 2-3 mile radius of our apartment. We have no children. Not having a car would remove the possibility of driving 20 miles away at the drop of a hat, but otherwise, our lifestyle would not be significantly impacted in the short term. Our lifestyle is enhanced by owning a car and having it around to use whenever we need it, but it isn&amp;#39;t dependent on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#39;t have rental reimbursement insurance now.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>5 Ways to Become a Better Programmer</title>
   <link href="http://jayraj.net/5-ways-to-Become-a-Better-Programmer"/>
   <updated>2014-03-04T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://jayraj.net/5-ways-to-Become-a-Better-Programmer</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For those of us who love coding and technology, there&amp;#39;s nothing quite like the thrill of getting better. There are many great coders out there and they offer a variety of advice for improving. This is what I put into action last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;1) Learn to Type&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tip comes from &lt;a href=&quot;http://steve-yegge.blogspot.com/2008/09/programmings-dirtiest-little-secret.html&quot;&gt;Steve Yegge&lt;/a&gt;. Known for his opinionated, wall-of-text, entertaining blog rants, Steve Yegge puts great stock in being able to type well and type fast. Yegge&amp;#39;s typing speed is probably the main reason he is able to write his massive blog posts without getting bored or exhausted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Implementing it&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before June 2013, I could type all the letters on my keyboard without needing to look down, but I didn&amp;#39;t use all my fingers. I was never able to break 55 wpm in typing tests because of this. I had been typing like that since I got my first computer at age 11.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used Typing Web&amp;#39;s excellent &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.typingweb.com/tutor/&quot;&gt;typing tutor&lt;/a&gt; app. It starts you off placing the fingers on the home row, typing letters at first, then words and finally sentences. Numbers and punctuation come later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;The result&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was really hard in the beginning, especially at work. I had to stay late a few times the first few weeks, to get work done on time. I kept at it and seven months later, I am back to my old 55-60 wpm speed. But now I use all my fingers. I&amp;#39;m sure I will get faster. It takes time to break 15 years of habit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;2) Learn (a) Lisp&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.paulgraham.com/avg.html&quot;&gt;Paul Graham&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.catb.org/esr/faqs/hacker-howto.html&quot;&gt;Eric Raymond&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://xkcd.com/224/&quot;&gt;xkcd&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://sites.google.com/site/steveyegge2/scheming-is-believing&quot;&gt;Steve Yegge&lt;/a&gt; (again) and many, many others say that learning Lisp will change you as a programmer. You will see everything differently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Implementing it&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I fully support learning for its own sake, it might be hard to ever be at a job where I need to use something like Common Lisp. Clojure, with its practical design outlook and JVM-ness, seemed an ideal compromise. It&amp;#39;s got real traction. I had seen it action a couple of years ago at grad school, where one of my colleagues used it with Processing to make cool looking sketches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I actually had previous history with Lisp. Training for new recruits at TCS followed (and as far as I know, still does), the beginner level programming course at MIT, which uses Scheme. At the time, fresh out of college, my previous programming education treated the different styles of programming (functional, object-oriented etc.) the way that old-school Darwinist biologists treated evolution. Every new form was an improvement over the previous, eventually leading to the ideal form: human beings/OOP. Coming from that background, Scheme was a giant WTF. &amp;quot;Why would anyone use functions to act like classes?&amp;quot;, I thought, and left it at that. I doubt the instructors at TCS knew the answer to that either; they just taught it because they were told to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Tim Ferriss, when learning something new, having the right material can make the difference between learning it well and giving up in frustration after a few tries. The koan-style problem website &lt;a href=&quot;http://4clojure.com&quot;&gt;4clojure.com&lt;/a&gt; is perfect for learning Clojure syntax. Another project, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/functional-koans/clojure-koans&quot;&gt;clojure-koans&lt;/a&gt;, and some &lt;a href=&quot;http://aphyr.com/posts/306-clojure-from-the-ground-up-state&quot;&gt;essays&lt;/a&gt; written by bloggers got me started. In December, I wrote a small &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jogjayr/ttt&quot;&gt;tic-tac-toe&lt;/a&gt; game in Clojure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;The result&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love it. I&amp;#39;m still barely a beginner, I don&amp;#39;t even fully grasp macros yet (according to Paul Graham, the most powerful feature of Lisp), and it&amp;#39;s still amazing. Lisp code looks...beautiful. Concise. Elegant. There&amp;#39;s nothing else like it. And now, having been exposed to this style of programming, I find it bleeding over into the way I write JavaScript (currently my main language).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;3) &lt;em&gt;Really&lt;/em&gt; understand CS theory&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;#39;t have a great teacher for Automata Theory, in college. I also had a lot going on at the time and slacked off. I got good marks in the exam by last-minute cramming, but I&amp;#39;ve never understood the whole deal with Turing machines and the rest of that. It felt like something was missing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing Automata Theory and Computer may not immediately help you with your work but you will be changed forever by the knowledge. Computers, and why we know they work, won&amp;#39;t be a mystery anymore. In a way, it&amp;#39;s like knowing how to build a house, then going back and studying Newtonian physics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Implementing it&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I signed up for the Automata Theory course on Coursera. Did most of the lectures and assignments, except the last couple of weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;The result&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is a bit of a mixed bag. I definitely understand computer science theory a lot more now. I was lax in doing the proofs in the course, so maybe I didn&amp;#39;t get as much out of it as I could have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;4) Get to know your tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one is just common sense. If you become more proficient with your everyday tools, and use features that you haven&amp;#39;t used before, it can take you less time to do the same work. Take a few minutes every weekend, and find a new feature in your daily tools that you never used before. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Implementing it&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use many tools. Sublime Text 2 is a major one; I do almost all my typing in it (haven&amp;#39;t tried upgrading to ST3 yet). There is a huge ecosystem of plugins and snippets and packages for it. The ones I found most useful: &lt;a href=&quot;http://emmet.io/&quot;&gt;Emmet&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jshint.com/install/&quot;&gt;JSHint&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/titoBouzout/SideBarEnhancements&quot;&gt;Sidebar&lt;/a&gt;. I also learned keyboard shortcuts for selecting text in different ways: column select, word select, selection within quotes, within tags and within the current (bracket) scope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the other tools I use: I switched from bash to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://fishshell.com/&quot;&gt;fish shell&lt;/a&gt;. I switched from the default OS X terminal to iTerm. And I also added &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alfredapp.com/&quot;&gt;Alfred&lt;/a&gt; to my workflow, to automate my work  (the jury is still out on this one, because I&amp;#39;ve also become better at shell scripting) and help me look up documentation more quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The result&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Faster work, less RSI, less boredom. Every minute I&amp;#39;ve spent studying keyboard shortcuts and other features has paid off many times over. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;5) &lt;a name=&#39;git&#39; class=&#39;hidden_link&#39;&gt;Get better at Git&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;If you&amp;#39;re still using SVN or CVS, you&amp;#39;re a sucker&amp;quot; - &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jayraj.net&quot;&gt;Some smart person&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I say &amp;quot;Git&amp;quot;, I don&amp;#39;t mean just Git, but that&amp;#39;s the distributed source control system I know best. Git obviously has a lot of momentum, and the sheer power that if offers over SVN makes you an order of magnitude more productive. Branching and merging, doing releases, working with other team members, hunting down bugs, creating clean histories, doing experimental work; everything is easier and faster with Git.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Implementing it&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been using Git for personal projects since 2011, but 2013 was the first time I got to use it in the workplace. I work with many Git wizards. My team uses the &lt;a href=&quot;http://nvie.com/posts/a-successful-git-branching-model/&quot;&gt;Gitflow&lt;/a&gt; model for releases. I discovered the magical tool that is &lt;code&gt;git rebase&lt;/code&gt; (especially in interactive mode) and how to use it to clean up development histories and make your merges go more smoothly. I learned how &lt;a href=&quot;http://git-scm.com/book/en/Git-Tools-Debugging-with-Git&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;git bisect&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; could save me a lot of manual work in figuring out where a bug was introduced. &lt;code&gt;git cherry-pick&lt;/code&gt; came in handy recently when I had to include some work from a branch without merging the whole branch in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;The result&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Git is fucking awesome. Even at my advanced beginner level of understanding it seems lightyears ahead of SVN. Creating branches for each feature and fix, code reviews before merges and frequent small commits now all feel like the right way to do write software.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>5 Reasons to Improve your Vim-Fu</title>
   <link href="http://jayraj.net/5-Reasons-to-Improve-your-Vim-Fu"/>
   <updated>2014-02-20T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://jayraj.net/5-Reasons-to-Improve-your-Vim-Fu</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yes, it&amp;#39;s 2014. No, logically, we shouldn&amp;#39;t be using text editors written in the fucking 1970s. I mean, seriously, how many other things made in the 70s are we still using now?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because there were no funny cat videos on the Web in those days, the (largely) bearded gurus of computing&amp;#39;s early days mostly read and wrote text. So they made tools that were exceptionally good for writing text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vim is something every Mac and Git-using programmer will encounter because it is the default editor for typing Git commit messages. We all know &lt;code&gt;i&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;:q&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;:w&lt;/code&gt;. Realistically, that&amp;#39;s all you need to write commit messages in Vim for the rest of your career. Congratulations, we&amp;#39;re done here! You can go. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or...read on. Because if you care to get even slightly better at Vim, there are so many rewards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;No GUI dependence - Vim, Emacs and other editors from the Unix golden-age (a term I pulled out of my ass), were developed in an era with no (or limited) availability of mice, monitors and so on. The bad - this means using a mouse can be odd (although I hear it&amp;#39;s better in Emacs than in Vim). The good - if you get good at Vim-ing, you never need to use a mouse again to manipulate text; and that is a &lt;em&gt;very good thing&lt;/em&gt; for your speed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Default Editor for Git - Vim is. So if you want to go beyond just typing commit messages, like re-ordering and squashing your commits using interactive rebase, you can either:
a) do it slowly and laboriously, using only &lt;code&gt;i&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Esc&lt;/code&gt;
b) (what I do) copy all the commit lines into Sublime, re-order and edit and paste them back in
c) Become a Vim badass and do it really fast in the terminal&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Expressiveness - Before Sublime, my editors of choice, in chronological order, were Notepad, Gedit, Notepad++, Aptana and Geany). Compared to those, Sublime&amp;#39;s multi-cursor selection, snippet support and shortcuts were like Arnold Schwarznegger in &lt;em&gt;Terminator&lt;/em&gt;: an unimaginably powerful weapon from the future. So imagine when I got to reading about Vim&amp;#39;s capabilities (using &lt;code&gt;vimtutor&lt;/code&gt;) and was confronted with &lt;code&gt;d2w&lt;/code&gt;. Delete 2 words and put the cursor at the beginning of the third words. And this was lesson 2. What. The. Fuck. &amp;quot;But what good is that&amp;quot;, you might say, &amp;quot;I&amp;#39;m never giving up Sublime, because it has so much that I like&amp;quot;. Well...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vintage Mode for Sublime - It&amp;#39;s Sublime made better with Vim. That&amp;#39;s like welding Batman&amp;#39;s Utility Belt to the best Swiss Army knife in the world. I think; I&amp;#39;m still trying it out and I will let you know in a future blog post&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vim is everywhere - You can&amp;#39;t always control your environment. If you SSH to an EC2 instance where you have to modify environment files or code, you can&amp;#39;t use Sublime easily. Meanwhile, &lt;code&gt;vim&lt;/code&gt; is right there, just waiting for you to use it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Convinced? Here&amp;#39;s how to get started:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The key to understanding Vim (and this is not an original insight from me) is realizing that there are two modes: a mode where you enter commands, and a mode where you type in text (yes, those are their &lt;em&gt;actual&lt;/em&gt; names). The advantage of this is you can both type text and execute commands without having to use too many modifier keys.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use &lt;code&gt;vimtutor&lt;/code&gt; - Usually comes with Vim on Mac OS X. Run it in the terminal and go through an approximately 30 minute tutorial that takes in  a lot of the basics. Vim basics, that is; crazy ways to insert and delete text, undo and redo and so much more. I might write a separate post just about vimtutor&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Start up vim (just run &lt;code&gt;vim&lt;/code&gt;), then type &lt;code&gt;:help&lt;/code&gt; to see more ways to learn. It has an extensive help section with clickable table of contents that cover everything in Vim.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Hashed DNA Database</title>
   <link href="http://jayraj.net/Hashing-DNA-Crimefighting"/>
   <updated>2013-06-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://jayraj.net/Hashing-DNA-Crimefighting</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There’s a simple solution to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npr.org/2013/06/03/188397999/supreme-court-rules-arrest-dna-collection-reasonable&quot;&gt;Supreme Court’s ruling that taking DNA swabs of arrestees is permissible&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a ruling that has privacy advocates &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techdirt.com/articles/20130603/16534123300/horrifying-supreme-court-ruling-lets-police-collect-dna-because-you-might-just-be-horrible-criminal.shtml&quot;&gt;up&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techdirt.com/articles/20130603/16534123300/horrifying-supreme-court-ruling-lets-police-collect-dna-because-you-might-just-be-horrible-criminal.shtml&quot;&gt;in&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aclu.org/criminal-law-reform/aclu-comment-maryland-v-king-decision&quot;&gt;arms&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are reasons to worry about this decision. Some are speculative, pessimistic or dystopian: it opens the door to a police state, it makes it easier for authorities to track your whereabouts and frame you. Some are genuine: DNA is private information about the very thing that makes a person who they are, and there are fears that insurance companies and even less benign parties may gain access to this information to misuse it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I’m in Silicon Valley, it’s almost obligatory to come up with a technological solution to this. The basic &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cigna.com/individualandfamilies/health-and-well-being/hw/dna-fingerprinting-in-a-criminal-investigation-zm2567.html#zm2567-sec&quot;&gt;DNA fingerprinting process&lt;/a&gt; is a 4-step procedure that ends with a nylon membrane with a pattern on it, which can be compared to existing patterns. I propose creating a national DNA fingerprint database, similar to the one the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fbi.gov/about-us/cjis/fingerprints_biometrics/iafis/iafis&quot;&gt;FBI has for regular fingerprints&lt;/a&gt;. The database should, by law, only be allowed to store a hash of a person’s DNA pattern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To revise (and for non-tech readers), a hash is what you get when you run a piece of information through a hashing algorithm. A hash of a given data set has 2 properties:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s unique&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can’t get the original data back just from the hash value&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, the hash of the string “I love tacos” using the MD5 algorithm is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;b5d19ec884a387e767811afbe097affc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you are given just “b5d19ec884a387e767811afbe097affc” you could never tell that it was generated by hashing “I love tacos”. You could also say with a high degree of certainty that only the string “I love tacos” would give you “b5d19ec884a387e767811afbe097affc”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do the same thing with DNA information (with a different, better algorithm, obviously) and the benefits are obvious:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Law enforcement has another tool to identify suspects uniquely. When they arrest a suspect, they swab him or her, a device calculates and stores the hash of the DNA on the swab and the swab is destroyed immediately. They compare the hash to hashes already in the database.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Privacy advocates are happy because it reduces DNA information to something as devoid of external meaning as a fingerprint. A DNA hash can’t betray anything about a person’s ancestry, probabilities of developing medical conditions or anything else that can be gleaned from a DNA sample.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone wins here. Hashed databases have to be the way to go.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Backbone View Collection - Part 3</title>
   <link href="http://jayraj.net/backbone-view-collection-part-3"/>
   <updated>2013-06-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://jayraj.net/backbone-view-collection-part-3</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In this series of posts on how I wrote a collection class for Backbone views, I covered the objectives of the enterprise in &lt;a href=&quot;http://jayraj.net/blog/2013/05/19/backbone-view-collection-part-1&quot;&gt;part 1&lt;/a&gt;. In &lt;a href=&quot;http://jayraj.net/blog/2013/05/19/backbone-view-collection-part-2&quot;&gt;part 2&lt;/a&gt; the Backbone ViewCollection accomplished its first goal: create a lot of child views of a specified type, off of a collection passed to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post will discuss how I event handling works with so many child views. I saw numerous blog posts and StackOverflow questions related to event binding when &lt;code&gt;empty&lt;/code&gt; is called on a jQuery object. For me, the most important bit of knowledge was that when you do the following &lt;a href=&quot;http://jsfiddle.net/jogjayr/3QfLc/1/&quot;&gt;JSFiddle&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;text language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;var $child_el = $(&amp;quot;#my_div&amp;quot;).on(&amp;quot;click&amp;quot;, function() {
    console.log(&amp;quot;clicked me&amp;quot;);
})
$(&amp;quot;#parent_elem&amp;quot;).html($child_el); //Clicking on the child will do nothing
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CHILD VIEW&amp;#39;S EVENTS ARE LOST! I suppose this is general knowledge among those familiar with the DOM&amp;#39;s secrets, but it was a revelation to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second revelation (in fact, as I started writing this blog post), is that the child views&amp;#39; events actually need to delegate to the parent. Previously, I used to do the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;text language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;var Backbone.ViewCollection = Backbone.View.extend({
    //other View Collection methods here

    //delegateEvents not only re-attaches the collections&amp;#39;s events
    //it also re-attaches childEvents without calling them individually
    delegateEvents: function() {
        Backbone.View.prototype.delegateEvents.call(this);
        _(this.childViews).each(function(view, index, childViews) {
            view.delegateEvents();
        });
    }
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://lostechies.com/derickbailey/2011/10/11/backbone-js-getting-the-model-for-a-clicked-element/&quot;&gt;this blog post&lt;/a&gt; by the inestimable Derick Bailey of KendoUI and MarionetteJS fame, I have realized that this my existing approach is COMPLETELY MORONIC. I will have to go back to the projects that inspired this library and fix it, but I will do it first here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason it&amp;#39;s so stupid is because when you attach an event to each individual child event:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your application uses a lot more memory. Each event listener is extra overhead.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The clue was in the method name &lt;code&gt;delegateEvent&lt;/code&gt;. I should be using the time-tested &lt;a href=&quot;http://davidwalsh.name/event-delegate&quot;&gt;event delegation pattern&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Backbone View Collection - Part 2</title>
   <link href="http://jayraj.net/backbone-view-collection-part-2"/>
   <updated>2013-05-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://jayraj.net/backbone-view-collection-part-2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;http://jayraj.net/blog/2013/05/19/backbone-view-collection-part-1&quot;&gt;part 1&lt;/a&gt; of this series, I explained what I wanted from a Backbone View Collection. The first and foremost thing was a common render method:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;text language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;Backbone.ViewCollection = Backbone.View.extend({
  childViews: [],
  render: function() {

    //The Backbone view class passed in that is 
    //used to generate child views
    var ItemViewClass = this.options.ItemView || Backbone.View;

    var me = this;
    _(me.collection).each(function(model, index, collection) {

    //for every model in the collection, create a new view
    var new_item_view = new ItemViewClass({model: model});

    //add it to the list of child views the collection holds
    me.childViews.push(new_item_view);

    //also add it to the view collection&amp;#39;s own HTML element
    me.$el.append(new_item_view.$el);
   });
  }
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This approach carries a couple of issues. The first one I faced was actually quite silly; setting &lt;code&gt;childViews&lt;/code&gt; to an empty array in the class definition results in &lt;strong&gt;every&lt;/strong&gt; instance of that class pointing to the same array. This is quite disastrous; all the child items of every instance of ViewCollection are added to the same array. We have to fix this, and it&amp;#39;s quite simple:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;text language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;Backbone.ViewCollection = Backbone.View.extend({
  render: function() {
  //all the stuff we wrote above...
  },
  initialize: function() {
    //this ensures every instance of ViewCollection has a fresh array of childViews
    this.childViews = [];
  }
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#39;s also another problem, and it has to do with how we pass &lt;code&gt;ItemView&lt;/code&gt; to ViewCollection. If we were to create a new ViewCollection like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;text language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;var PokedexView = new Backbone.ViewCollection({
  collection: Pokedex,
  ItemView: PokemonView 
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;then the line:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;text language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;var ItemViewClass = this.options.ItemView || Backbone.View;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;works perfectly. The &lt;code&gt;options&lt;/code&gt; attribute of a Backbone view is composed of the object you pass into the constructor. But what if you don&amp;#39;t call the constructor directly? Consider the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;text language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;var PokedexView = Backbone.ViewCollection.extend({
  collection: Pokedex
});
//a specific type of Pokedex that uses a grid layout
var PokemonGridItemView = Backbone.View.extend({});
var PokedexGridView = PokedexView.extend({
  ItemView: PokemonGridItemView
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, &lt;code&gt;this.options.ItemView&lt;/code&gt; is &lt;code&gt;undefined&lt;/code&gt;. This does not bode well for being able to build complex class hierarchies with ViewCollection, so we have to modify what we wrote just a little bit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;text language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;//Either `this` is an instance of ViewCollection, in which case ItemView is an `option`
//or `this` is an instance of a another type derived from ViewCollection
//or use the plain-old Backbone.View class
var ItemViewClass = this.options.ItemView || this.ItemView || Backbone.View;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Same thing applies for collection. So&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;text language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;_(me.collection).each(...)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;won&amp;#39;t work every time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having learned all this, here&amp;#39;s ViewCollection now:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;text language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;Backbone.ViewCollection = Backbone.View.extend({
  render: function() {

    //The Backbone view class passed in that is 
    //used to generate child views
    var ItemViewClass = this.options.ItemView || this.ItemView || Backbone.View;
    var collection = this.options.collection || this.collection;
    var me = this;
    _(collection).each(function(model, index, collection) {

      //for every model in the collection, create a new view
      var new_item_view = new ItemViewClass({model: model});

      //add it to the list of child views the collection holds
      me.childViews.push(new_item_view);

      //also add it to the view collection&amp;#39;s own HTML element
      me.$el.append(new_item_view.$el);
    });
  },
  initialize: function() {
    this.childViews = [];
  }
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be continued...&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Backbone View Collection - Part 1</title>
   <link href="http://jayraj.net/backbone-view-collection-part-1"/>
   <updated>2013-05-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://jayraj.net/backbone-view-collection-part-1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I love &lt;a href=&quot;http://backbonejs.org&quot;&gt;Backbone.js&lt;/a&gt; for many reasons: it&amp;#39;s lightweight, small (it&amp;#39;s the first open-source library whose code I&amp;#39;ve actually completely read), super simple to get started with and has a very active community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Backbone Views leave a bit to be desired because they do very little. As the &lt;a href=&quot;http://backbonejs.org/#View&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; itself says &amp;quot;Backbone views are almost more convention than they are code&amp;quot;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One particular pain point I&amp;#39;ve had is the inability to manage collections of views. There already exist a &lt;a href=&quot;http://marionettejs.com/&quot;&gt;number&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;http://chaplinjs.org/&quot;&gt;solutions&lt;/a&gt; that provide you a nice way to build applications with more structure that what Backbone alone will give you. I decided to write Backbone ViewCollection for 2 reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wanted to write it myself, to learn how&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Backbone ViewCollection provides a better way of managing Backbone views while still keeping the application pure Backbone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;What should a View Collection Do?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the things I wanted from a View Collection class:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Renders a Backbone Collection into a Backbone View that is composed of further, child views. Each model in the collection corresponds to a child view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;code&gt;render&lt;/code&gt; method that calls &lt;code&gt;render&lt;/code&gt; on all its child elements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Handles &lt;code&gt;delegateEvent&lt;/code&gt; and all the other crap associated with it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manages child view creation and destruction and prevents memory leaks or zombie views&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Child views can be anything - as long as they are nodes of the parent view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an example of what such a class would do:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;text language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;var Pokemon = Backbone.Model.extend({});
var Pokedex = new Backbone.Collection({
    model: Pokemon;
});
var PokemonView = Backbone.View.extend({
    render: function() {
        //some code to render a Pokemon&amp;#39;s info
    }
});
var PokedexView = new Backbone.ViewCollection({
    childView: PokemonView,
    collection: Pokedex
});
//This will create an instance of PokemonView for each model in
//the Pokedex collection and call its render() method
PokedexView.render();
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the coming blog posts, I will describe how I made my ViewCollection.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Poor Little Rich Kid</title>
   <link href="http://jayraj.net/Poor-Little-Rich-Kid"/>
   <updated>2012-05-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://jayraj.net/Poor-Little-Rich-Kid</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;A Rock and a Hard Place&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AT&amp;amp;T head honcho Randall Stephenson put his foot in his mouth on Wednesday, May 2, while demonstrating his commitment to shareholders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At a conference hosted by the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.milkeninstitute.org&quot;&gt;Milken institute&lt;/a&gt; the New York Times &lt;a href=&quot;http://bits.blogs.nytimes.com/2012/05/04/att-randall-stephenson/&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; Stephenson bemoaning the decision to give iPhone users all-you-can-eat data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My only regret was how we introduced pricing in the beginning, because how did we introduce pricing? Thirty dollars and 
you get all you can eat. And it’s a variable cost model. Every additional megabyte you use in this network, I have to &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;invest capital.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not much sympathy for him there. The iPhone was exclusive to AT&amp;amp;T for 4 years. People who hated AT&amp;amp;T would become subscribers because of the iPhone. And when its massive data sucking caused dropped calls for everyone, people not only put up with it, they &lt;em&gt;bought their own mini cell towers and operated them at their own cost&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not content with pissing off the masses with his griping about having to spend so fuckin&amp;#39; much to provide service to his customers, Stephenson railed about the unfairness of it all, with iMessage eating into his sweet, sweet texting margins. Woe is me, indeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You lie awake at night worrying about what is that which will disrupt your business model. Apple iMessage is a classic 
example. If you’re using iMessage, you’re not using one of our messaging services, right? That’s disruptive to our &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;messaging revenue stream&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That clearly didn&amp;#39;t go down well with commenters on the article either. Because text messages are so ridiculously lucrative for carriers, and carry such high margins, it&amp;#39;s not even funny. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Randall Stephenson was speaking at an industry conference surrounded by fellow worshippers of capitalism (the Milken institute &amp;quot;believes in the power of capital markets to solve urgent social and economic challenges and improve lives&amp;quot;). His remarks were clearly right for the setting, and right by his shareholders, but he might&amp;#39;ve stopped to consider the impression formed with a broader audience, who clearly see this as greedy bellyaching. (Just see the comments on the article)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Farewell Forbes</title>
   <link href="http://jayraj.net/Farewell-Forbes"/>
   <updated>2012-04-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://jayraj.net/Farewell-Forbes</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Hoping it will be Proved Wrong&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adam Hartung did a number on Sony on Forbes.com. In an article titled &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forbes.com/sites/adamhartung/2012/04/20/sayonara-sony-how-industrial-mba-style-leadership-killed-once-great-company/&quot;&gt;Sayonara Sony: How Industrial, MBA-style Leadership Killed a Once Great Company&lt;/a&gt;, he first talked about Sony&amp;#39;s past glories, and why they&amp;#39;re struggling now. But his article doesn&amp;#39;t hold up to logical scrutiny at all. (Beware: Long post ahead)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, Sony&amp;#39;s achievements: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sony improved solid state transistor radios until they surpassed the quality of tubes, making good quality sound available very reliably, and inexpensively&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sony developed the solid state television, replacing tubes to make TVs more reliable, better working and use less energy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sony developed the Triniton television tube, which dramatically improved the quality of color (yes Virginia, once TV was all in black &amp;amp; white) and enticed an entire generation to switch.  Sony also expanded the size of Trinitron to make larger sets that better fit larger homes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sony was an early developer of videotape technology, pioneering the market with Betamax before losing a battle with JVC to be the standard (yes Virginia, we once watched movies on tape)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sony pioneered the development of camcorders, for the first time turning parents – and everyone – into home movie creators&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sony pioneered the development of independent mobile entertainment by creating the Walkman, which allowed – for the first time – people to take their own recorded music with them, via cassette tapes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sony pioneered the development of compact discs for music, and developed the Walkman CD for portable use&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sony gave us the Playstation, which went far beyond Nintendo in creating the products that excited users and made “home gaming” a market.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hartung argues that a lack of product vision, and management by numbers has led to the company&amp;#39;s downfall. Here he blames Japanese industrial culture, which focused on improving manufacturing processes and reducing costs, but led to little innovation elsewhere. Quite how Sony made all their technological breakthroughs (including &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quantum_tunnelling#History&quot;&gt;research&lt;/a&gt; that led to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leo_Esaki&quot;&gt;Nobel prize&lt;/a&gt;) if they were complicit in this &amp;quot;neglect research, lower costs&amp;quot; mentality, is left unexplained. In addition, Sony prided itself on selling quality goods at a premium. Sure, they pursued manufacturing and supply-chain improvements, much like Apple does today, but the savings only bolstered their already heaving margins. In this, they distinguished themselves from other Japanese companies of the era. They also ruthlessly dumped businesses with low margins, such as pocket calculators (a decision Morita bemoaned later in his autobiography, because it put Sony back when the age of computers began).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next he goes on to point out Sony&amp;#39;s history of pushing proprietary formats: Betamax, ATRAC (which Hartung calls Sony MP3, for some reason), and most recently, Blu-ray. He fails to mention the CD-ROM standard, on which Sony collaborated with Philips. He also forgets that once Betamax died, Sony happily got behind VHS and sold VCRs for many years, even winning the landmark &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_shifting&quot;&gt;time-shifting&lt;/a&gt; judgement from the US Supreme Court. So even losing a format war in the past didn&amp;#39;t hinder the selling of products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, ex-CEO Howard Stringer gets it in the neck for cutting costs and laying off people. It may be true that Stringer might not have been what the company needed culturally or from a &amp;quot;big picture&amp;quot; standpoint. But the Sony he took over had become an unwieldy, unfocused giant with too many businesses and units (what the hell were they doing selling insurance and renting helicopters?). It could be argued that the company needed a dose of discipline (not at the expense of innovation).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, the real reason Sony is struggling is that they never &amp;quot;got&amp;quot; the age of computers. They remained stuck in their ways of producing pretty-looking gadgets that were as sleek and small as possible (sound familiar?), without realizing that these gadgets could now be full-featured computers, with software on them. For that matter, I don&amp;#39;t think they&amp;#39;ve ever really understood software or the Internet. These things came after the company&amp;#39;s initial successes, and not many of the early employees studied at American universities, or worked at American corporations that were performing research on the Internet, Unix and C. I don&amp;#39;t think Sony ever saw themselves as a pure consumer electronics company either, seemingly attempting to model themselves on the likes of GE (especially when you look at their disparate businesses), RCA or other Japanese conglomerates. Having missed the information age boat once, they then proceeded to do so again, with the mobile age, choosing to partner with Ericsson and giving the whole setup some stepmotherly treatment. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having fallen behind technologically in a very important area (software), they also neglected one of their core strengths: industrial design. The Walkman, the Trinitron TV or the first &amp;quot;pocketable&amp;quot; transistor radio were stunning achievements of industrial design in consumer electronics. Why don&amp;#39;t we see that anymore from Sony? It could be, as Hartung claims, because of cost-cutting, but it could also be because they no longer have a product-focused CEO like Morita, or his successor Norio Ohga. In this at least, Hartung is correct. &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>How to Meet Deadlines</title>
   <link href="http://jayraj.net/How-to-Meet-Deadlines"/>
   <updated>2012-04-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://jayraj.net/How-to-Meet-Deadlines</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Coming up next: Groupon&amp;#39;s Accounting Scandals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dan Frommer decided to write a story about what everyone else knows; Google is scared of Facebook. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;#39;t news to anybody really. Therefore, quite why he felt the need to write a story titled &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/why_facebook_terrifies_google.php&quot;&gt;Why Facebook Terrifies Google&lt;/a&gt; is beyond this blog. Because it&amp;#39;s really quite simple: people spend more time on Facebook, Facebook knows more about those people, Facebook can serve better ads. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure it&amp;#39;s nice to include a few screenshots from FB&amp;#39;s ad creation interface, to demonstrate what kind of targeting can be done. But if the bar for what is &amp;quot;news&amp;quot; has been lowered to this level, expect a piece on how SourceForge is changing the world of open-source softwa...oh. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What does Anecdotal Mean?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sparkling journalism from the one-Pulitzer-a-year New York Times, as they reported that growing numbers of children of immigrants to the US are moving back to their parents&amp;#39; homelands in search of opportunity. People in India know this of course, thanks to Shahrukh Khan in &lt;em&gt;Swades&lt;/em&gt;. But surely Mr. Khan was an exception; not many have a Gayatri Joshi waiting for them. What kind of numbers are we talking about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2012/04/16/us/more-us-children-of-immigrants-are-leaving-us.html?pagewanted=all&quot;&gt;Many U.S. Immigrants’ Children Seek American Dream Abroad&lt;/a&gt;, Kirk Semple promises much, quoting an expert as saying &amp;quot;We&amp;#39;ve gone beyond anecdotal evidence.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Number of pieces of anecdotal evidence in the article: 6&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Number of pieces of statistical evidence: 1 &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(and that, a figure about the number of people of Indian descent that arrived in India in 2010, without regard to length of stay, purpose of visit, and with no context of past numbers given)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For shame. &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Did you Expect any Better from TV?</title>
   <link href="http://jayraj.net/Did-you-Expect-any-Better-from-TV"/>
   <updated>2012-04-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://jayraj.net/Did-you-Expect-any-Better-from-TV</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Don&amp;#39;t Feel like Writing? Produce Reality TV&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gawker&amp;#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://gawker.com/5901613&quot;&gt;Ryan Tate&lt;/a&gt; dug into &lt;a href=&quot;http://pandodaily.com/2012/04/05/an-open-letter-to-randi-zuckerberg-how-could-you-do-this-to-real-entrepreneurs/&quot;&gt;Sarah Lacey&lt;/a&gt; and the rest of Silicon Valley, saying what the rest of us know already; they&amp;#39;re dying to become famous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaving out the irony of a website that unflinchingly employs provocative titles to drive page views to basically tame pieces of fluff accusing someone else of attention-seeking behaviour, there is a kernel of truth in this. Lacey&amp;#39;s attack on Randi Zuckerberg&amp;#39;s upcoming reality TV show was pointless for a number of reasons. Just because she worked at Facebook and her brother built it, doesn&amp;#39;t make she&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;selling out&amp;quot; Silicon Valley. Who cares how tech companies are depicted on TV? Does it really matter if companies in the Valley are shown partying and taking off their shirts all the time?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, Gawker being Gawker, they had to be &amp;quot;reliably informed&amp;quot; that Lacey tried and failed to create her own tech reality TV show. The obvious conclusion to be drawn (if you work at Gawker), is that anyone who attacks Zuckerberg&amp;#39;s show really just wants the fame for themselves. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog thinks they should all shut up and get back to work. And let Zuckerberg do her job. &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>No One Really Knows a Thing</title>
   <link href="http://jayraj.net/No-One-Really-Knows-a-Thing"/>
   <updated>2012-04-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://jayraj.net/No-One-Really-Knows-a-Thing</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Slight Difference of Opinion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gizmodo: &lt;a href=&quot;http://gizmodo.com/5900989&quot;&gt;Not Shocking: Google Could Already Be Eyeing a Motorola Hardware Sale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Business Insider: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/google-plans-to-make-substantial-investment-in-motorola-not-sell-it-2012-4?op=1#ixzz1rmqdMsxq&quot;&gt;Google &amp;#39;Plans To Make Substantial Investment&amp;#39; In Motorola&amp;#39;s Phone Business, Not Sell It&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Consequences will Never be the Same</title>
   <link href="http://jayraj.net/Consequences-will-Never-be-the-Same"/>
   <updated>2012-04-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://jayraj.net/Consequences-will-Never-be-the-Same</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;You done goofed! I backtraced it!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Counter-terrorism expert and writer Richard A. Clarke served up some wonderful BS today. In an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2012/04/03/opinion/how-china-steals-our-secrets.html&quot;&gt;Op-Ed&lt;/a&gt; piece for the New York Times, he held forth on the number of trade secrets and technology American companies are losing to hackers. Quoting Gen. Keith B Alexander, he calls it &amp;quot;the greatest transfer of wealth in history&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where he starts sounding less like an &amp;quot;expert&amp;quot; and more like the &amp;quot;Consequences Will Never Be the Same&amp;quot; dad. What he suggests is patent nonsense: &amp;quot;the United States government could stop files in the process of being stolen from getting to the Chinese hackers&amp;quot;, by having the DHS scan every file coming in and going out, a la a cyber customs force.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, if it was that simple, piracy wouldn&amp;#39;t exist. If ordinary people can get &lt;i&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/i&gt; for free from foreign websites, it&amp;#39;s reasonable to assume skilled Chinese uber-hackers could do the reverse without much trouble, no matter who&amp;#39;s watching the pipes. Then there&amp;#39;s also the issue of the DHS having to install filters on every line in and out, maintain a database of &amp;quot;sensitive files&amp;quot; which they would have to amass from companies, who need to be comfortable putting proprietary information into the hands of a government body that&amp;#39;s no more likely to be secure than the companies themselves. The whole idea of a government cyber border patrol manning a nation&amp;#39;s digital frontiers is laughable; an idea from the original &lt;i&gt;Tron&lt;/i&gt; or &lt;i&gt;VR Troopers&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There isn&amp;#39;t a single idea in this whole enterprise that doesn&amp;#39;t have a faint touch of the ridiculous. From gems like: &amp;quot;If government agencies were authorized to create a major program to grab stolen data leaving the country, they could drastically reduce today’s wholesale theft of American corporate secrets&amp;quot;, to the only flaw in the plan being &amp;quot;privacy advocates&amp;quot;. The only person who stands to benefit from any such legislation is Richard A Clarke himself. An expert like him could stand to mint a small fortune from consulting engagements, if such legislation or executive orders were considered. It seems about par for a man who has Amazon affiliate links to his own book on his own &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.richardaclarke.net/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; (seriously, who does that?).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, Mr. Clarke unwittingly offers a much simpler solution himself. He notes that the SEC recommends companies to disclose breaches in security. Perhaps it should be made mandatory. The only ways to get CEOs to pay attention to regulatory issues are the threat of jail time, or a drop in the stock price. Repeated breaches, when revealed by force of SEC regulation, will do plenty to ensure the latter. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;420&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/HGVeJ7w4R6U&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&#39;allowfullscreen&#39;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The World of DIY Drones</title>
   <link href="http://jayraj.net/The-World-of-DIY-Drones"/>
   <updated>2012-03-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://jayraj.net/The-World-of-DIY-Drones</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;These Ain&amp;#39;t Your Older Sibling&amp;#39;s Drones&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I took my first steps into the world of DIY drones. Saw a link on a colleague&amp;#39;s GChat status (thanks Andrew!) - &lt;a href=&quot;http://tacocopter.com&quot;&gt;tacocopter.com&lt;/a&gt;. I still don&amp;#39;t know if they&amp;#39;re for real, but this West coast startup purports to deliver tacos using flying robots. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I dove headlong into the world of DIY drones to find out if it was possible. Turns out, information is really sparse on the ground (weak laugh). &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.google.com/p/arducopter/&quot;&gt;Arducopter&lt;/a&gt; is a hotbed of activity; an open-source UAV autopilot project. This thing is ridiculously futuristic-sounding: &amp;quot;scripted waypoints, GPS, sonar sensor for automated takeoff and landing capability&amp;quot;. And it starts at $600! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a theoretical range of 4km in some configurations, and minimum payload capabilities of 500gm (although these two figures were obtained separately, so I don&amp;#39;t know if both are possible), food delivery using drones is tantalizingly within reach of the existing technology. It just needs a determined startup to max out these capabilities, solve the security problems, set up charging stations (maybe on cellphone towers?) and provide food delivery as a service (FDaS?) to restaurants. So restaurants can focus on doing what they do best: making the food. The drone flies in, picks up the food, drops it off and zips back to its charging station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you think about it, using an entire car and person to deliver a single parcel of food is rather wasteful. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regulatory issues will undoubtedly crop up. The FAA will get involved. And of course, the potential for lawsuits when a drone inevitably falls out of the sky and conks somebody in head. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: What you inevitably get for posting too early: &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.google.com/p/arducopter/&quot;&gt;Tacocopter is a fake service&lt;/a&gt; and the article confirms my suspicions that the regulatory and safety issues make this nearly impossible in the near future. Shame. &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>How to Solve a Quality Problem</title>
   <link href="http://jayraj.net/How-to-Solve-a-Quality-Problem"/>
   <updated>2012-03-06T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://jayraj.net/How-to-Solve-a-Quality-Problem</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Amateur Hour is Clearly Better than the Pros&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Logical reasoning is an overrated skill for Wired magazine. Mike Isaac&amp;#39;s story &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/gadgetlab/2012/03/mit-google-release-new-tools-to-fix-androids-quality-control-problem&quot;&gt;MIT, Google Release New Tools to Fix Android’s Quality-Control Problem&lt;/a&gt; is an example of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting with the reasonable premise that Android apps don&amp;#39;t look as good as iOS ones, Isaac first stretches the meaning of the word &amp;quot;new&amp;quot; while
describing Android App Inventor, considering Google originally released it well over a year ago. The only difference now is that MIT Media Lab
has taken over the project because Google couldn&amp;#39;t be bothered to do it anymore. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, is the absurd conclusion drawn that making Android app making accessible to more people will improve the quality of apps produced. 
NPD&amp;#39;s Ben Arnold is even quoted as saying &amp;quot;It&amp;#39;s kind of what Tumblr or Blogger has done for web development.&amp;quot; That pretty much sums it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fairness, Isaac does also mention the new Android Design guidelines website, something which will probably do a great deal more to 
advance the cause of Android app design.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Those are Some Mighty Big Feet</title>
   <link href="http://jayraj.net/Those-are-Some-Mighty-Big-Feet"/>
   <updated>2012-03-05T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://jayraj.net/Those-are-Some-Mighty-Big-Feet</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Redefing a &amp;quot;shoestring&amp;quot; budget&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.geekwire.com/2012/startup-spotlight-28yearold-entrepreneur-guides-greencupboards-profits-shoestring&quot;&gt;Geekwire&lt;/a&gt; really played 
fast and loose with the word &amp;quot;bootstrapping&amp;quot; today applying it to eco-product retailer &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.greencupboards.com/&quot;&gt;Greencupboards&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If $288,000 is shoestring, it&amp;#39;s safe to say those are shoes you could be murdered over.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>No Sarcasm Today</title>
   <link href="http://jayraj.net/No-Sarcasm-Today"/>
   <updated>2012-03-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://jayraj.net/No-Sarcasm-Today</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Who Wants a Warm Slice of Raspberry Pi&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read this piece in Engadget today about a $25 desktop computer system named the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.raspberrypi.org/&quot;&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;. The only thing
I can say is &amp;quot;How cute!&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s a little circuit board that you can plug a monitor, keyboard and mouse into. It uses an SD card for storage and micro-USB cellphone
charger for power. It&amp;#39;s the geek&amp;#39;s equivalent of seeing a puppy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The BBC has the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-17190334&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Waah!</title>
   <link href="http://jayraj.net/Waah%21"/>
   <updated>2012-02-24T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://jayraj.net/Waah!</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Exclusive: No one cares&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Delightful &lt;a href=&quot;http://parislemon.com/post/18182094905/the-wall-street-journal-is-fucking-bullshit&quot;&gt;little tantrum&lt;/a&gt; today from noted Apple (Designed in California&amp;trade;) fanboy, investor and blogger MG Siegler. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ll summarize it here as &amp;quot;The Wall Street Journal published an article based on a story I broke but didn&amp;#39;t give me credit or a link. So now onwards I will do the same. And yeah, the journalist who wrote the article should join Techcrunch or PandoDaily because she&amp;#39;s really nice.&amp;quot; No need to thank me for saving you 5 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>New Research Reveals Billfold is "Vulnerable"</title>
   <link href="http://jayraj.net/New-Research-Reveals-Billfold-is-Vulnerable"/>
   <updated>2012-02-11T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://jayraj.net/New-Research-Reveals-Billfold-is-Vulnerable</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Billfold Susceptible even Without &amp;quot;Rooting&amp;quot;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More accurately, it&amp;#39;s the past couple of days as technology blogs have been quick to pounce on the fact that &lt;a href=&quot;https://zvelo.com/blog/entry/google-wallet-security-pin-exposure-vulnerability&quot;&gt;Google Wallet is hackable&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like most alarmist &amp;quot;research&amp;quot; done these days, it comes with a caveat: the phone needs to be rooted. Or failing that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theverge.com/2012/2/9/2787758/second-google-wallet-security-vulnerability-confirmed-affects-all&quot;&gt;stolen phones could have pre-paid credit stolen&lt;/a&gt; if the thief reinstalls the Wallet app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google, in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://googlecommerce.blogspot.com/2012/02/protecting-your-payments-with-google.html&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; today, made the quite reasonable argument that manufacturers disable root access to phones for precisely reasons like this. Any user that voluntarily roots their phone should know what they are getting into. And unlike a real wallet, you can put a security code on a cell phone to prevent someone from using it even if they steal it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So basically what tech blogs are saying is: &amp;quot;Even though I&amp;#39;ll definitely lose all my cash, credit cards and ID if my physical wallet is stolen, Google Wallet is the one that&amp;#39;s &amp;#39;vulnerable&amp;#39;&amp;quot;. Gotta drive those pageviews people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having said that, I don&amp;#39;t think mobile payments are such a swell idea right now, or even in the near future. Having a single point of failure makes me uncomfortable. If my battery dies or my phone is stolen, or dropped into a toilet bowl, or eaten by a bear, not only can I not call for help, I can&amp;#39;t even pay for a cab to get me home.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>It's Only Chutzpah when Google Does It</title>
   <link href="http://jayraj.net/Only-Chutzpah-when-Google-Does-It"/>
   <updated>2012-02-09T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://jayraj.net/Only-Chutzpah-when-Google-Does-It</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Google and Harvey Dent&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fair amount of heat in the press about Google applying the squeeze on Apple through Motorola&amp;#39;s patent horde. Noted Apple (Designed in California&amp;trade;) fanboy &lt;a href=&quot;http://pandodaily.com/2012/02/08/harvey-harvey-harvey-dent/&quot;&gt;MG Siegler&lt;/a&gt; accused Google of being Two-Face from Batman because of this new strategy, because a year ago their public policy stance was that software patents are harmful and should not exist. And now they&amp;#39;re demanding 2.25% of every iPhone and iPad sold. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clearly, according to Siegler, companies shouldn&amp;#39;t be allowed to change their minds, ever, even when the other side isn&amp;#39;t playing by the same rules. If you declare yourself to be a pacifist, you should stand idly and let thugs beat you senseless. At least he admits that Apple is doing the same thing to Samsung and other Android OEMs, that being Steve Jobs&amp;#39; wish. They&amp;#39;re not even offering to license their patents and want their competitors to be shut down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And Forbes magazine&amp;#39;s editor &lt;a href=&quot;http://tech.fortune.cnn.com/2012/02/09/chutzpah-google-also-wants-2-25-of-every-iphone-sale/&quot;&gt;Philip Elmer-Dewitt&lt;/a&gt; thinks it&amp;#39;s fair for Apple to assert their patents to shut down competition because those are proprietary works that the Cupertino giant never agreed to make industry standard, unlike Motorola&amp;#39;s fundamental patents, which Moto promised to never assert when they were granted. Again, we see the opinion from a respected voice that companies should not be allowed to change their minds, even when the competition is playing by different rules&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Motorola agreed to license their patents. Google will continue to do so, but will change the price. It&amp;#39;s no more or less fair than suing someone over pinch-to-zoom interaction.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The New Stasi</title>
   <link href="http://jayraj.net/The-New-Stasi"/>
   <updated>2012-02-08T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://jayraj.net/The-New-Stasi</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;&amp;quot;Deleted&amp;quot; Doesn&amp;#39;t Really Mean Deleted? Well, duh.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forbes.com/sites/kashmirhill/2012/02/07/the-austrian-thorn-in-facebooks-side/&quot;&gt;Forbes.com&amp;#39;s&lt;/a&gt; Kashmir Hill shone the spotlight on one Max Schrems, a 24-year-old Austrian law student and privacy activist. When he takes a break from dancing to polka tunes, drinking coffee with chocolate, eating wiener schnitzels, and telling his Facebook friends that he did these things, Schrems cracks open his massive tomes on European privacy law to find new ways to harass Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all began very simply for young Max when he studied at Santa Clara University for a semester and learned that Facebook&amp;#39;s lawyers knew precisely f*ck-all about privacy law in Europe. He also found an obscure page on Facebook where European users can get every bit of info that Facebook has about them, as per the law on the Continent. Upon submitting a copy of his passport, driver&amp;#39;s license, birth certificate, scuba certification and even a hairdresser&amp;#39;s license that they made him get for this express purpose, Schrems received a thousand (1000) page file with all his information. He said it was like the Stasi&amp;#39;s files, because of the detail and scope of the information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What vexed our young crusader the most is that some pieces of info had been tagged as &amp;quot;[DELETED]&amp;quot; but Facebook clearly still had them. He feels this is an outrage. Max, I don&amp;#39;t know if you know how the Internet works, but Facebook provides this wonderful service, that costs a lot to operate, for free. In return for this, they will log every single thing you do on their platform, and keep it for all eternity. Call it the new social contract for the Internet. If you don&amp;#39;t like it, don&amp;#39;t do anything you don&amp;#39;t want others to know on Facebook. Or just stop using Facebook. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Google to Pay You for Your Information&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it&amp;#39;s about damn time too. Google&amp;#39;s new &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/landing/screenwisepanel/&quot;&gt;Screenwise&lt;/a&gt; program offers Amazon gift certificates in return for letting Google watch your every move through their Chrome browser. I guess it&amp;#39;s cool for those who are OK with it and really want the gift certificates. Though one does wonder if there&amp;#39;s a minimum usage requirement. I mean, what if I sign up, but only use Firefox to browse the Web?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>TIL - Facebook tells Lies</title>
   <link href="http://jayraj.net/TIL-Facebook-tells-Lies"/>
   <updated>2012-02-06T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://jayraj.net/TIL-Facebook-tells-Lies</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;It&amp;#39;s All Semantics Really&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dealbook.nytimes.com/2012/02/06/those-millions-on-facebook-some-may-not-actually-visit/&quot;&gt;Andrew Ross Sorkin&lt;/a&gt;
was freaking out over Facebook&amp;#39;s claims that it has 483 million active users everyday, implying it was disingenuous. The reason: Facebook counts &amp;quot;Like&amp;quot;-ing or sharing via the &amp;quot;Share on Facebook&amp;quot; button as being active on Facebook. Since these people don&amp;#39;t see any ads, they don&amp;#39;t make revenue directly for FB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, am I really more active if I login to Facebook and paste a link into my status update (theoretically, since I don&amp;#39;t have an account), than if I click on the Share button from the article directly? Sorkin concedes that even non-FB domain engagement is valuable information to FB but insists that investors deserve to also have signed-in user numbers. IMHO, it&amp;#39;s really not that big of a deal, except to stock analysts who want to seem like they&amp;#39;re doing more work by examining another metric. It&amp;#39;s entirely possible for Facebook to roll out an AdSense-style advertising network, making it irrelevant whether users actually visit Facebook.com. Speaking of which, how come Facebook doesn&amp;#39;t have something like AdSense? Or is it just my small minded-ness to think AdSense is still relevant?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Could this mean free porn forever?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A California woman&amp;#39;s fight against the copyright mafia shakedown has brought to light an interesting legal question: can porn be copyrighted at all?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must admit the headline, &lt;a href=&quot;http://torrentfreak.com/you-cant-copyright-porn-bittorrent-defendant-insists-120206/&quot;&gt;You Can&amp;#39;t Copyright Porn, Harassed BitTorrent Defendant Insists&lt;/a&gt;, had me thinking of those people who upload Taylor Swift songs to Youtube and write &amp;quot;No copyrights intented[sic]&amp;quot;. Instead, Liuxia Wong of California, who was told that a copyright infringement lawsuit for allegedly pirating Hard Drive productions&amp;#39; cinematic masterpiece &lt;em&gt;Amateur Allure Jen&lt;/em&gt; could go away for $3400, fought back with a stunning claim: porn can&amp;#39;t be copyrighted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copyright was intended &amp;quot;To promote the Progress of Science and useful Arts&amp;quot;, and a California circuit court ruled that &amp;quot;obscene works did not promote the progress of science and art&amp;quot; (would love to see a link to this judgement somewhere, but the article did not say). If you put 2 and 2 together, this seems to imply that porn can&amp;#39;t be copyrighted. Now it&amp;#39;s unlikely that such a judgement will ever come to pass, so I think the most likely outcome is Hard Drive productions slinking away, tail between legs. &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>I'm Confused as to What We've Been Doing So Far</title>
   <link href="http://jayraj.net/I%27m-Confused-as-to-What-We%27ve-Been-Doing-So-Far"/>
   <updated>2012-02-03T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://jayraj.net/I'm-Confused-as-to-What-We've-Been-Doing-So-Far</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Startups - Conspiracy or Extended Hackathon?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hard-hitting stuff from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.siliconvalleywatcher.com/mt/archives/2012/02/the_dirty_littl_1.php&quot;&gt;Tom Forenski and Silicon Valley Watcher&lt;/a&gt; as they expose the current startup mania (which this writer is a part of), as nothing more than an elaborate front for recruiting tech talent and making their investors rich, writing: &amp;quot;Just one $25 million payday from the sale of a startup will more than cover an Angel investor&amp;#39;s loss from a hundred dud $25K investments&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He does close on a heartwarming, cheer-the-underdog note by adding:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Silicon Valley&amp;#39;s dirty little secret is that the startup boom is mostly a disguised jobs fair that directly benefits the big corporations. &amp;gt; Occasionally, an innovative startup makes it past this stage but it has to be so bad that no one wants it -- not even for its team. It&amp;#39;s   &amp;gt; from among those ugly ducklings that the swans of the new age emerge: FB, Goog, Twitter, Yahoo! and others -- no one wanted them at first, &amp;gt; then they couldn&amp;#39;t get enough of them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This last bit is slightly disingenuous. None of the companies mentioned above were shunned because of a lack of engineering talent; instead it was their (apparent) lack of a revenue model that made investors wary. Good job otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Lolwut? Story of the Day&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessweek.com/news/2012-02-03/facebook-punters-put-shares-at-35-with-bono-ringing-bell.html&quot;&gt;Reports&lt;/a&gt; of Facebook&amp;#39;s IPO price being the subject of bets by leading UK bookmaker Paddy Power sounds odd on the face of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why would someone bet on the price of a security at a bookmaker&amp;#39;s when they can just do it in the real market? Granted, it&amp;#39;s a bet on the issue price, which is the one price set, not by the open market, but by what Facebook&amp;#39;s bankers think will move the most paper. But it still seems slightly backward and redundant to place bets on stock prices with a bookie, when you can do the same with a broker. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Pirates ARE Romantic Figures&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techdirt.com/articles/20120126/09565417551/why-piracy-is-indispensable-survival-our-culture.shtml&quot;&gt;Quick line about this article&lt;/a&gt;
from pirate-sympathizers Techdirt, who argue that DRM will logically result in a loss of our digital heritage as archivists are unable to preserve the past. History will thank the pirates for doing their thing. Fight the man. We shall overcome.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Wasn't Facebook in the News Today?</title>
   <link href="http://jayraj.net/Wasn%27t-Facebook-in-the-News-Today"/>
   <updated>2012-02-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://jayraj.net/Wasn't-Facebook-in-the-News-Today</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Yesteryear&amp;#39;s Hot Consumer Electronics Firm Shakes Things Up&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clearly most of the tech world is focused elsewhere, but I thought this was the more interesting piece of news. Once the dominant force in consumer electronics, maker of shiny silver gadgets that people coveted and carried in their pockets, Sony &lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2012/02/01/back-to-basics-sony-appoints-kazuo-hirai-ousts-stringer/&quot;&gt;fired its British CEO Sir Howard Stringer&lt;/a&gt;, elevating their electronics division head Kazuo Hirai. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The past 10-15 years have not been kind to the once-great company. They never &amp;quot;got&amp;quot; the Internet or the mobile revolution, and are suffering for it. TC recommends that Sony head back to the safety of its Playstation platform and dominate games, but that&amp;#39;s no way for a company like them to go. Microsoft and its Xbox division have scads of cash and traction, and console gaming isn&amp;#39;t growing like it once used to. It would be sad to see them try to make a go of it in mobile or social gaming. No, there&amp;#39;s only one way forward for them, IMHO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sony was known for its stunning, clean designs, elegant gadgets and ability to push the boundaries of what was possible with electronics (they created the first pocketable radio, the first portable music player and many other firsts). They must try to get back to those roots. Software isn&amp;#39;t their strength, and it&amp;#39;s fortuitous that HP recently decided to open-source WebOS, a lost little orphan looking for a loving home. Sony have the cash to throw at making it a viable platform and the pure engineering ability to design and build devices of outstanding quality. Let&amp;#39;s hope they haven&amp;#39;t lost their stomach for the fight; it&amp;#39;s all-too-easy for Apple (Designed in California &amp;trade;) at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Facebook IPO Follows Formula&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the trail blazed by tech companies in recent years, Facebook (dubbed the IPO of the century) finally filed to go public today. The filing displayed all the tropes of a tech company&amp;#39;s filing: letter from founder setting out idealistic vision - check, CEO taking a $1 salary but becoming filthy rich - check, promises to maintain a certain unique company culture - check, appeals to investors to take into account that it&amp;#39;s more than just a company or an investment - check.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FB is a mammoth, of that there is no doubt. They have large profits and equally impressive margins ($1 billion and 27%, respectively, last year). Apart from letting investors and early employees cash out and get rich, they don&amp;#39;t really need to IPO, with numbers like that. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m not providing links for this because it&amp;#39;s easily the biggest tech news story since Steve Jobs&amp;#39; death.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>You Lost Files? Boo-f\*ckin-hoo</title>
   <link href="http://jayraj.net/You-Lost-Files"/>
   <updated>2012-01-30T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://jayraj.net/You-Lost-Files</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Feds will Soon Approve Shooting Through Hostages&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the continuing fallout from the Megaupload takedown, the feds have essentially told users: &amp;quot;We don&amp;#39;t care about your treasured memories and important work documents&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Megaupload is unable to pay its hosting bills due to their assets being frozen, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/feds_to_megaupload_users_tough_luck.php&quot;&gt;ReadWriteWeb reported today&lt;/a&gt;. Because of payment defaults, their hosting company may soon start deleting data. And since the government wasn&amp;#39;t given search warrants for Megaupload&amp;#39;s users&amp;#39; files, they can&amp;#39;t back them up either. The bottomline: if someone doesn&amp;#39;t change their minds soon, people are going to lose stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blaming users for storing their files on Megaupload is like blaming injured innocent bystanders in a shootout between cops and drug dealers: &amp;quot;Well obviously, you shouldn&amp;#39;t have been walking through such a dangerous neighbourhood.&amp;quot; To those who say it&amp;#39;s not right to compare a computer user losing files to a 13-year old getting shot on the way to school, I would say that it&amp;#39;s also not right to compare drug dealing with someone illicitly downloading the odd movie or song. If society has decided that it&amp;#39;s not right to put innocent lives at risk when pursuing suspects of heinous crimes, then it follows that it&amp;#39;s not right to put innocent files at risk when pursuing suspects of copyright crimes.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Safest Job in the World</title>
   <link href="http://jayraj.net/The-Safest-Job-in-the-World"/>
   <updated>2012-01-29T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://jayraj.net/The-Safest-Job-in-the-World</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Code Language for &amp;quot;We don&amp;#39;t like your kind &amp;#39;round here&amp;quot;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2012/01/29/us/bay-area-technology-professionals-cant-get-hired-as-industry-moves-on.html&quot;&gt;NY Times article&lt;/a&gt;
today reported the travails of older technology workers in Silicon Valley who find work hard to come by. Despite most
half-decent 20 year-old coders having job offers coming out of their ears and noses, older workers are discriminated against
by Web companies because many don&amp;#39;t have the skills needed today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The jury is out on whether older people are less adept at coding and adapting than young &amp;#39;uns. Cynics will say that companies
prefer healthy 20-somethings (lower health insurance costs) with no social lives and lower salary expectations, and who grew up texting in 
Ruby on Rails (or something). Proponents of the older crowd note that programming, like most disciplines, is about 
pattern recognition and more experience means longer and more varied exposure to patterns, which means older coders are 
more productive. But that&amp;#39;s not what we&amp;#39;re talking about here. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HR uses phrases like: &amp;quot;Are they going to get to do what they love to do for fun at work?&amp;quot;, that people say are code-words for 
discrimination (of course no 40 year-old is going to get excited about Node.js; they think it&amp;#39;s asinine to use a language like
Javascript, on a barely 2-year old platform). 
LinkedIn wants employees to be &amp;quot;entrepreneurial&amp;quot;; which is a bit like a zoo director saying he wants his tigers to be
&amp;quot;vegetarian&amp;quot;. It&amp;#39;s easy to see what job doesn&amp;#39;t need you to be familiar with a dictionary, as long as you sound impressive.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>It's Not Even OK for A/B Testing</title>
   <link href="http://jayraj.net/Its-Not-Even-OK-for-AB-Testing"/>
   <updated>2012-01-28T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://jayraj.net/Its-Not-Even-OK-for-AB-Testing</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;You&amp;#39;re Not You When You&amp;#39;re Being Paid By Someone Else&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet tw-align-center&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;You’re not you when you’re hungry @&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/snickersUk&quot;&gt;snickersUk&lt;/a&gt;#hungry#spon   &lt;a href=&quot;http://t.co/PUZnINcl&quot; title=&quot;http://lockerz.com/s/177408824&quot;&gt;lockerz.com/s/177408824&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Rio Ferdinand (@rioferdy5) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rioferdy5/status/161840144628973568&quot; data-datetime=&quot;2012-01-24T15:57:51+00:00&quot;&gt;January 24, 2012&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rio Ferdinand of Manchester United (sigh) was responsible for a storm in a tempest (shield your eyes if you expect cliches used correctly) 
today when he promoted a Snickers bar on his Twitter feed. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paul Sawers at &lt;a href=&quot;http://thenextweb.com/twitter/2012/01/28/brands-may-be-paying-celebrities-for-tweets-but-whos-paying-twitter/&quot;&gt;The Next Web&lt;/a&gt;
wrote that the UK authorities might have a problem with any implied (ie, not explicit) endorsement as being unfair. It&amp;#39;s safe to say that
won&amp;#39;t happen (as many commenters on the post pointed out), because of the #spon hashtag, coupled with the fact that it was so out
of the ordinary for Rio (sample tweet: &amp;quot;Morning tweeps! Back from training! Wazza in my #pocket. #stayonyourfeet #piershasmoobs&amp;quot;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless Rio was doing this for charity, it&amp;#39;s also worth wondering how much Snickers paid him to piss off his 2 million followers.
And pissed off they were. It must be a lot, because he&amp;#39;s one of the highest paid players in the Premier League.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Fight! Fight! Fight!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;YC-backed Curebit were caught red-handed being very naughty. The firm&amp;#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/#!/allangrant&quot;&gt;Allan Grant&lt;/a&gt;
was embroiled in a pitched Twitter battle with RoR creator &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/#!/dhh&quot;&gt;David Heinemeier Hansson&lt;/a&gt; 
(whose middle name is the answer to the question: &amp;quot;What should I do if I get 4 Es and 2 Is in Scrabble?&amp;quot;) about copied 
HTML code, design and even (shamefully) hot-linked images from one of Hansson&amp;#39;s 37Signals sites (or something like that).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grant started off defensive (&amp;quot;we&amp;#39;re a small company&amp;quot;), then quickly discovered that the leg he thought he had to stand on (he&amp;#39;d hot-linked to this leg too)
did not exist (it started 404-ing). With the tide of popular Intertweets opinion turning against him, he quickly capitulated
(or at least, pretended to). For me, this has ended in disappointing fashion. Hansson is a racecar driver and who wouldn&amp;#39;t have
paid to see the two of them race down the Golden Gate Bridge to settle this? 
(give me a break, I don&amp;#39;t know jack about SFO&amp;#39;s geography). &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>$167/year raises are newsworthy</title>
   <link href="http://jayraj.net/%24167-year-raises-are-newsworthy"/>
   <updated>2012-01-26T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://jayraj.net/$167-year-raises-are-newsworthy</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;New Employee Discount Program at Apple&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Splendid stretching of the definition of &amp;quot;news&amp;quot; by &lt;a href=&quot;http://9to5mac.com/2012/01/25/tim-cook-at-todays-town-hall-starting-in-june-apple-employees-get-500-off-macs-250-off-ipads/&quot;&gt;9to5Mac&lt;/a&gt;.
Apple (Designed in California&amp;trade;) CEO Tim Cook announced a new employee benefit at the company&amp;#39;s internal town hall
yesterday. Starting June, all employees will get $500 off (in addition to their existing 25% discount on all company products)
on Macs and iPads. The catch: they can only use it once every 3 years. This works out to about $167/year/employee. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we&amp;#39;re on the topic of employee benefits, the gold standard must surely be Google, who announced a &lt;a href=&quot;http://articles.businessinsider.com/2010-11-09/tech/30024423_1_google-ceo-googlers-eric-schmidt&quot;&gt;$1000 (post-tax) Christmas
bonus and an across-the-board 10% salary hike&lt;/a&gt; 
2 years ago. Compared to that, the most valuable company in the world giving out $167 in store credit is a bit laughable. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;AT&amp;amp;T Try to be More Tone-Deaf than MPAA&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AT&amp;amp;T CEO Randall Stevenson is doing his best to cement his company&amp;#39;s position at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://content.usatoday.com/communities/technologylive/post/2011/12/survey-at38t-rates-last-in-customer-satisfaction/1&quot;&gt;bottom of the customer satisfaction
rankings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still peeved at the breakdown of the T-Mobile acquisition thanks to the FCC, Stevenson announced that AT&amp;amp;T would have to
increase data prices because of a lack of capacity, because they weren&amp;#39;t allowed to acquire T-Mobile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a capacity-constrained environment we will manage usage-based data plans, increased pricing and managing the speeds of 
the highest volume users. These are all logical and necessary steps to manage utilization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As has already been pointed out though, AT&amp;amp;T has actually reduced their per-unit price for data on all plans. The only effect
of the &amp;quot;price increase&amp;quot; has been to force customers onto more expensive plans, even though they pay less per unit of data on
these plans. Clearly capacity isn&amp;#39;t a problem at AT&amp;amp;T if they can afford to give out more for less. Instead as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/att_ceo_randall_stevenson_blasts_fcc_hints_at_high.php&quot;&gt;ReadWriteWeb&lt;/a&gt;
points out, this is more of a punishment to their customers and the FCC. Or a tantrum. However you want to look at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog suggests that AT&amp;amp;T take some of that $40 billion they were planning to spend on buying T-Mobile and put some more
cell towers up. Maybe give out some &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.cnet.com/8301-30685_3-20001242-264.html&quot;&gt;femtocells for free&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Everyone should be above average</title>
   <link href="http://jayraj.net/Everyone-should-be-above-average"/>
   <updated>2012-01-25T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://jayraj.net/Everyone-should-be-above-average</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Friedman wades into the jobs vs tech debate&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thomas Friedman of the New York Times displayed a masterclass today in phoning it in. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his column titled &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2012/01/25/opinion/friedman-average-is-over.html&quot;&gt;Average is Over&lt;/a&gt;, he first explained that technology has been eating away at many jobs (like it has done for the past 100 years) and that this has gotten even faster in the last 10.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then he trots out this revolutionary idea that anyone of average talent and skill is doomed to dim professional prospects. Now there&amp;#39;s some  sound career advice kids. And it&amp;#39;s not like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/if-youre-an-average-worker-in-this-forever-recession-youre-going-straight-to-the-bottom-2012-1&quot;&gt;Business Insider reported Seth Godin saying the exact same thing&lt;/a&gt; 
a week ago. Wait...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, as a commenter on the column points out, it&amp;#39;s mathematically impossible for EVERYONE to be above average. That means that a significant portion of the population are going to be stuck in menial jobs forever. In fairness to Friedman, he may have meant &amp;quot;above average&amp;quot; when considering the entire world&amp;#39;s population. Getting a degree in English from the Southern Arkansas University (no offense) may not make you above average in the US (or even Arkansas), but still puts you pretty high up the chain when considering the entire world&amp;#39;s workforce. Now if only graduates of the Southern Arkansas University could move to China...&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Should Everyone Else Just Give Up?</title>
   <link href="http://jayraj.net/Should-Everyone-Else-Just-Give-Up"/>
   <updated>2012-01-24T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://jayraj.net/Should-Everyone-Else-Just-Give-Up</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Apple Makes a F*ckload of Money&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Noted blogger, venture capitalist and Apple (Designed in California&amp;trade;) fanboy MG Siegler called Apple&amp;#39;s first quarter 2012 results 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://parislemon.com/post/16424622119/a-holy-fucking-shit-quarter&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;A &amp;#39;Holy Fucking Shit&amp;#39; Quarter&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;. The numbers are impressive indeed; $13 billion profits on $46 billion sales. Or in other words, more money than God. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They now have close to a $100 billion in the bank. It might not be a bad idea for the EU to ask them for a bailout. Or help other poor people. C&amp;#39;mon people. You can re-open the charity department again. And give someone else a chance to win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;I, for one, welcome our new robot drivers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/magazine/2012/01/ff_autonomouscars/all/1&quot;&gt;great&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2012/01/24/technology/googles-autonomous-vehicles-draw-skepticism-at-legal-symposium.html&quot;&gt;deal&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thestar.com/article/1120427--bmw-creates-robot-car-that-can-drive-itself&quot;&gt;press&lt;/a&gt; recently has made it clear that autonomous cars are just around the corner. The NYT covered a symposium dedicated to the legal implications of this new technology.
The benefits are clear: safety, fuel and time efficiency, greater car-sharing and privacy for sexy times in the
backseat without having to rent a limo. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s safe to say that this technology is at least 6 years away from even narrow-spread adoption. Nevada is the only state, so far, to legalize autonomously driven cars. Other state legislatures will begin to consider the issue over the next couple of years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that all the other issues: insurance, police stops, deer on the road and even the Chinese restaurant/stop sign problem (I don&amp;#39;t know if they&amp;#39;re the same thing, but have superficial similarities in that sharing access to a resource leads to a starvation condition and indefinite waiting), will work themselves out eventually. What I&amp;#39;m curious about is the process used to certify or give a &amp;quot;driver&amp;#39;s license&amp;quot; to these programs. Will they be held to the same standards that human beings are? Is it really possible to verify that a driving program has no bugs and will perform perfectly under all conditions?
Or will it just be &amp;quot;good enough&amp;quot; if the program is better than the &amp;quot;average driver&amp;quot;? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we get into thorny territory. Google have claimed that their car has driven 200,000 miles without accidents, but that&amp;#39;s not really statistically significant (unless they have more data they haven&amp;#39;t released yet). In &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.motorists.org/other/crash-data&quot;&gt;1995&lt;/a&gt; (yes, I know, old as hell, but I&amp;#39;m lazy), the US had 1.5 fatal accidents per 100 million vehicle miles. If anyone wants to do more detailed analysis, they are welcome to, but 200k is hardly conclusive that the program is safe. Unless...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More speculation here: I&amp;#39;m no computer vision expert; is it possible to train such a system on video data? If it is, then Google must have a wealth of such data, thanks to StreetView. And in that case, the system may only have driven 200,000 real world miles but tested on many many more.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>RIM's new Dear Leader...</title>
   <link href="http://jayraj.net/RIMs-Dear-Leader"/>
   <updated>2012-01-22T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://jayraj.net/RIMs-Dear-Leader</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;RIM appoint new Dear Leader&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the vastness of the frozen north, the Republic of Imaginary Millions&amp;#39; (RIM) Politburo selected Thorsten Heins as their general secretary.
Heins replaces Jim Balsille, one of the founding fathers of the Republic, and Mike Lazaridis. Like his predecessors, Heins, retains his 
firm belief in the nation&amp;#39;s destiny, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theglobeandmail.com/globe-investor/at-research-in-motion-a-new-ceo-vows-to-silence-the-doomsayers/article2310968/&quot;&gt;declaring&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a fantastic growth story and it’s not coming to an end. What you will see with me is rigour and flawless execution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RIM is a major exporter of fruit, primarily Blackberries. Unfortunately, the world&amp;#39;s demand for Blackberries has slumped even as
the market for fruit, especially Apples, has grown. The embattled nation has had to face defections, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bgr.com/2011/06/30/open-letter-to-blackberry-bosses-senior-rim-exec-tells-all-as-company-crumbles-around-him/&quot;&gt;public shamings&lt;/a&gt;
and the draining of its treasury. Although some developing nations, such as India, are still pursuing &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forbes.com/sites/kashmirhill/2012/01/09/leaked-memo-claims-phone-companies-let-india-spy-on-u-s-emails/&quot;&gt;strategic security alliances&lt;/a&gt;
with the Republic, and even buying their old hardware, most of the Western world regards the nation as a power in terminal decline. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It remains to be seen whether Mr. Heins (hereafter, known as Dear Leader), will be able to breathe life back into the Republic of 
Imaginary Millions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Filesonic Running for Cover&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like ants from a broken anthill, file-sharing sites are scrambling to get out of the Justice Department and Big Content&amp;#39;s giant cross-hairs.
The two have declared war on every single website and service that offers file uploading and downloading, leaving the likes &lt;a href=&quot;http://torrentfreak.com/filesonic-kills-file-sharing-after-megaupload-arrests-120122/&quot;&gt;Filesonic&lt;/a&gt;
quivering in their boots. Filesonic has suspended file download capability, allowing users to only access their personal files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This explains why Today I Read couldn&amp;#39;t download the latest installment of Dr. Do-me-a-little. For research. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Joel Spolsky&amp;#39;s SOPA-smart idea&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;StackOverflow and FogCreek Software founder, and software writer &lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/u/0/117114202722218150209/posts/4GgaRiSyaTf&quot;&gt;Joel Spolsky&lt;/a&gt;
offered possibly some of the best solutions to SOPA/PIPA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specifically, he proposed a counter-attack by lobbying to abolish software patents, introduce punitive legislation for patent trolls,
enshrine linking to content in a law protecting free speech, and also called on Web companies who want to support pro-them candidates
to offer free advertisement, so that they aren&amp;#39;t so beholden to other people for campaign funding. In my opinion, that last one is
just a different way of funding campaigns, and it&amp;#39;s not difficult to see a future where Google would call a majority of the shots through
Youtube. Or, in an ironic twist, the content providers might get the last laugh by employing Hulu for this purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either way, it&amp;#39;s good to see that someone&amp;#39;s looking for a positive reaction to the whole thing, instead of resigning the industry to
fight the MPAA every couple of years.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Apple Destroys American middle-class</title>
   <link href="http://jayraj.net/Apple-Destroys-American-middle-class"/>
   <updated>2012-01-21T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://jayraj.net/Apple-Destroys-American-middle-class</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;New York Times Blames Apple for America&amp;#39;s Manufacturing Woes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maverick stuff from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2012/01/22/business/apple-america-and-a-squeezed-middle-class.html?pagewanted=all&quot;&gt;New York Times&lt;/a&gt; today, as they laid out a narrative of America falling from its industrial greatness due to the flight of high-tech manufacturing to Asia. And leading the exodus, according to this narrative, was the world&amp;#39;s most valuable technology company Apple (Designed in California&amp;trade;). They acknowledge that Apple kept production in the family till as recently as 2002, but efficiencies and labor shortages drove them to the Orient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Times painted a terrifying picture of thousands of Chinese workers roused from their dorms at midnight by shouting, grey-uniformed, jackbooted Germans to accommodate Herr Jobs&amp;#39; newest demands. Many commenters described it as &amp;quot;slave labor&amp;quot; ignoring that the definition of slavery is involuntary servitude. IMO the term is appropriate for child prostitutes in Thailand or Cambodia, but over the top for workers at Foxconn; they are only slightly less fortunate than Wal-Mart workers in America. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s also unfair to target Apple or even the computer electronics industry. It wasn&amp;#39;t the first industry to do it. General Electric, 
that stalwart of American manufacturing and symbol of American ingenuity,  started the obsession with &amp;quot;shareholder value&amp;quot; 
and began to offshore manufacturing in the late 70s and early 80s. For various reasons, the home appliances  industry, machine tools, 
steel, shipbuilding and countless others began the march out of the US long before Americans had heard  of the Internet. 
And even when there are opportunities for high-tech manufacturing in new industries, like solar power, the US has (cliches ahoy!) 
managed to shoot itself in the foot and hand the initiative to other countries. Yes, China has terrible labor protections, 
but that hasn&amp;#39;t stopped Germany or Japan competing with them to be the shopfloor of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;MPAA Threatens to Stop Paying for Senators&amp;#39; Private Jets, Mistresses and Ponies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those who count on quote &amp;#39;Hollywood&amp;#39; for support need to understand that this industry is watching very carefully who&amp;#39;s going to
stand up for them when their job is at stake. Don&amp;#39;t ask me to write a check for you when you think your job is at risk and then &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;don&amp;#39;t pay any attention to me when my job is at stake&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So spake former Senator, now MPAA mouthpiece, Chris Dodd. Threatening the vengeance of Thor, Iron-Man and the Punisher on all Congressmen who dared defy the MPAA&amp;#39;s edicts to pass SOPA/PIPA into law, Dodd (curiously, in another life, co-sponsor of legislation that &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dodd%E2%80%93Frank_Wall_Street_Reform_and_Consumer_Protection_Act#Overview&quot;&gt;protected consumers from big bully banks&lt;/a&gt;) singlehandedly dragged the MPAA&amp;#39;s previously squeaky clean name through mud. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I only wish lobbyists in India were this explicit. &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Apple, Google, Adobe set up informant networks</title>
   <link href="http://jayraj.net/Apple-Google-Adobe-informant-networks"/>
   <updated>2012-01-20T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://jayraj.net/Apple-Google-Adobe-informant-networks</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Fallout from the Megaupload takedown&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Ars Technica, 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/news/2012/01/why-the-feds-smashed-megaupload.ars&quot; title=&quot;Why the feds smashed Megaupload&quot;&gt;Nate Anderson&lt;/a&gt;, 
does a great piece on analyzing the specific timing of the Megaupload crackdown, with his sources implying that 
it wasn&amp;#39;t a coincidence that it happened a day after Congress&amp;#39; SOPA/PIPA debacle.
&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kim_Schmitz&quot; title=&quot;Kim Dotcom&quot;&gt;Kim Dotcom&lt;/a&gt; is a great name, it has to be said. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over at CNET 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.cnet.com/8301-31322_3-57362437-256/anonymous-goes-nuclear-everybody-loses/&quot; title=&quot;Anonymous Megaupload&quot;&gt;Molly Wood&lt;/a&gt;
criticized Anonymous&amp;#39; actions in DDoS-ing the Justice Department, MPAA, RIAA, Boy Scouts of America and half a dozen nuns
at a mission in Costa Rica. IMHO, no one except Justice Department, MPAA and RIAA employees, and reporters doing 
research, ever accesses those websites. Despite a scary looking screenshot from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.akamai.com/html/technology/dataviz1.html,&quot; title=&quot;Akamai Internet Monitor&quot;&gt;Akamai&amp;#39;s Internet monitor&lt;/a&gt;, 
it&amp;#39;s evident that the US has actually had fewer attacks in the last 24 hours (not sure how Akamai defines an &amp;quot;attack&amp;quot;) than parts
of the world that have had nothing to do with these events, to wit Brazil, Peru, China, Russia and Taiwan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Google-Apple-Adobe Poaching Antitrust Lawsuit&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2012/01/19/damning-evidence-emerges-in-google-apple-no-poach-antitrust-lawsuit/&quot; title=&quot;Google Apple Poaching&quot;&gt;Techcrunch&lt;/a&gt;
reported that the Department of Justice found documentary evidence of &amp;quot;no-poaching&amp;quot; agreements between some of the Valley&amp;#39;s
highest-profile companies, among them Google, Apple, Adobe, Intuit, Lucasfilm, Pixar and Intel. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The companies agreed not only to not steal each others&amp;#39; employees but even notify an applicant&amp;#39;s current employers,
a move one would associate with the likes of Foxconn or Soviet Russia. Presumably, the offending employees are then
sent off to gulags/iPhone-assembly factories with n-hexane. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From lobbying to loosen immigration laws for skilled workers to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codecademy.com/&quot;&gt;funding companies&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.cnet.com/8301-13772_3-57358837-52/nyc-high-school-will-train-badly-needed-software-engineers/&quot;&gt;even high schools&lt;/a&gt; 
dedicated to teaching people how to program computers, tech companies are pulling out all the stops to keep programmer 
costs down. I don&amp;#39;t know much about AI but given the incentives and economics of the thing,
you have to figure that somewhere along the line, someone will surely teach computers how to program themselves 
to a sufficiently high skill level. Hopefully, that won&amp;#39;t happen in my lifetime, but the odds aren&amp;#39;t good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Apple&amp;#39;s Foray into Textbooks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2012/01/a-brief-history-of-textbooks-or-why-apples-new-textbook-experience-is-actually-revolutionary/251662/&quot;&gt;Megan Garber&lt;/a&gt;
in The Atlantic reckons that Apple&amp;#39;s new approach to textbooks is revolutionary. The reason: textbooks become personal
because students can write in them and keep them even after they&amp;#39;re done with the course. While I agree that there&amp;#39;s
some value in getting to keep a textbook forever, the fact remains that once the student leaves school, she must buy an iDevice or read it on a computer screen from iTunes. There&amp;#39;s no escaping Apple&amp;#39;s walled garden. And in a world with Wikipedia, why would anyone restrict themselves to their history textbook as their sole source of information on
the Mexican-American war?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, the author&amp;#39;s arguments in favor of digital textbooks are contradictory. On the one hand, she asserts that
the Web age has de-emphasized the need to retain information and paper textbooks frame education as an 
&amp;quot;act of consumption, rather than exploration&amp;quot;. But putting video, audio and &amp;quot;interactive content&amp;quot; (a catch-all term 
for stuff that lights up, jumps around and tries to make algebra seem less like work), into a medium that by its 
very definition has boundaries, doesn&amp;#39;t change any of those facts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some textbooks are &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Computer-Networks-5th-Andrew-Tanenbaum/dp/0132126958&quot;&gt;timeless&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Modern-Operating-Systems-Andrew-Tanenbaum/dp/0136006639/ref=ntt_at_ep_dpt_1&quot;&gt;classics&lt;/a&gt;. But if
most learning outside school is by reading things on the open Web, shouldn&amp;#39;t learning in schools occur through the same 
medium? The concept of a textbook is outdated, in my opinion. A textbook is its author&amp;#39;s opinion of the best way to teach 
someone something. Putting it on an iPad doesn&amp;#39;t change this, nor does it turn learning into &amp;quot;exploration&amp;quot;. 
Great teachers do that. Students who ask insightful questions, and are serious about learning, do that.
Engaged parents do that. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A totally open Web isn&amp;#39;t the answer (blocking pr0n, for instance, is important), but what about an educational
search engine that is carefully curated to let students find relevant information? All we have here (mixed metaphors ahoy!) 
is the world&amp;#39;s largest technology company peddling their walled-garden Kool-aid to administrators in an effort 
to hook kids to their stuff early on.  &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Inaugural Today I Read</title>
   <link href="http://jayraj.net/Inaugural-Today-Read"/>
   <updated>2012-01-18T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>hhttp://jayraj.net/Inaugural-Today-Read</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today I created my Jekyll based blog for the first time. All the cool kids are doing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m not sure if this is really much better than Wordpress (although no MySQL + Git sounds pretty sweet)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Julian Assange on Rolling Stone magazine&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rollingstone.com/politics/news/julian-assange-the-rolling-stone-interview-20120118&quot; title=&quot;Assange on Rolling Stone&quot;&gt;Julian Assange&lt;/a&gt;, 
founder of Wikileaks, international hacker and possesor of the coolest white hair around, spoke to Rolling Stones magazine. 
Some of what he says is sensible: 
&amp;quot;people determined to be in a democracy, to be their own governments, must have the power that knowledge will bring&amp;quot;. 
Some of it is exactly the kind of thing that a rumoured egomaniac would say: &amp;quot;I don&amp;#39;t think I have a massive ego&amp;quot;. Great interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Instagram on WP7 before Android?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eminently speculative stuff from FastCompany about &lt;a href=&#39;http://www.fastcompany.com/1809035/could-instagram-come-to-windows-phone-before-android&#39;&gt;Instagram Coming to Windows Phone before Android&lt;/a&gt;
The reasons: WP7 looks better and Microsoft has the cash to incentivize Instagram sufficiently. I&amp;#39;m going to file this under a &amp;quot;maybe&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&amp;quot;Better than the real sport&amp;quot; video of the day&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zorbing is fun. Football is fun. Obviously you have to put them together. Right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/xIl45f6i1PU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&#39;allowfullscreen&#39;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>